Nate Micinski, M.A.

227 S. Catalina Ave., Unit 5 Pasadena, CA 91106

Phone: 424-262-2566 Email: nmicinski@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/DearLorditsNate

Portfolio: natemicinski.com

SUMMARY

Developer for both financial causes and user-focused web applications. Graduate of the UCLA Extension Full-Stack Bootcamp versed in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, jQuery, Git, and GitHub. I have over five years of experience in nonprofits building positive and genuine donor relationships through thoughtful, tactful, and empathic relationship management. I bring this same authentic communication to my web development by prioritizing attention to detail, fostering supportive atmospheres, and building products that make user's lives better.

EDUCATION

UCLA Extension Full-Stack Bootcamp Expected graduation May 2019

M.A., American Culture Studies (GPA of 4.0) Bowling Green State University (BGSU) Emphasis on Internet Cultures and Subcultural Theory

B.S., Integrative Liberal Studies (GPA of 3.57) Grand Valley State University (GVSU) Emphasis on Cultural Studies and Political Economy, Minor in Philosophy

LANGUAGES AND TECHNOLOGIES

• HTML

• CSS

JavaScript

¡Query

Bootstrap

Node.js

• Git

GitHub

RECENT PROJECTS

Traveler Check

A currency conversion check for your travels.

Site: https://dearlorditsnate.github.io/TravelerCheck/

Source: https://github.com/DearLorditsNate/TravelerCheck

• Materialize, OpenWeatherMap API, Open Exchange Rates API, Yandex Translate API

Ten-Question Tatooine Trivia

A jQuery and JavaScript trivia game with a Star Wars theme.

Site: https://dearlorditsnate.github.io/TriviaGame/

Source: https://github.com/DearLorditsNate/TriviaGame

• jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

GifTastic

A simple UI that allows users to request gifs of their choice by hitting the Giphy API.

Site: https://dearlorditsnate.github.io/GifTastic/

Source: https://github.com/DearLorditsNate/GifTastic

• Giphy API, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, LocalStorage

WORK EXPERIENCE

Development Manager March of Dimes, Glendale

2017-present

 Manage and cultivate high-value and high-profile donor relationships, coordinate and execute premiere fundraising events, and use data-driven best practices to achieve revenue growth and sustainability.

Development Specialist

2017

Southern California Public Radio, Pasadena

 Planned, supported, and executed major fundraising events, worked directly with mid-level donors, and engaged in systems and data analysis to promote aggressive organizational growth and development goals for the Major Gifts team.

Development Coordinator

2016-2017

National Multiple Sclerosis Society, Los Angeles

• Worked directly with participants, fundraisers, and local businesses to increase revenue and exposure of the organization and achieve marked strategic goals.

Executive Assistant to the CEO

2014-2016

Beyond the Block, Inc., San Francisco

• Designed and maintained organization's website, managed implementation and utilization of Salesforce for data aggregation and analysis, collaborated directly with the CEO to facilitate the growth, sustainability, public exposure, and impact of the organization.

Teaching Assistant

2012-2014

School of Cultural and Critical Studies, BGSU

• Planned and taught a section of Introduction to American Culture Studies, a course that surveyed historical and current cultural events and artifacts to help students facilitate critical inquiry into the challenges and possibilities inherent in a multicultural society.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Outstanding communication and interpersonal skills.
- Extensive experience working and collaborating in a team setting.
- Extensive public speaking experience.